Finding aid to the Pro-Life Alliance records CA.MS.00309
Smith College Archives
Pro-Life Alliance records
1985-1998
Smith College Archives
Pro-Life Alliance
CA.MS.00309
1.042 linear feet (3 containers)
Records contain budget proposals, pamphlets, flyers, minutes, photographs, clippings, and correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records of the Pro-Life Alliance were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College Senate chartered the Pro-Life Alliance in 1990, and the organization held its first meeting the following fall. The organization became inactive during the autumn of 1997. Clea Emerson-Farley, Class of 1997 and club secretary, compiled the majority of these files. The Pro-Life Alliance organized an annual Pro-Life 5-College Conference, actively attended pro-life conferences at other universities (such as Harvard and Brown), participated in Boston's annual Respect Life Walk, distributed pro-life literature throughout the Smith community, and brought in speakers such as journalist Kathleen Howley from the Boston Globe and Teresa Donovan, an active member of the Massachusetts Citizens for Life.
Scope and Contents
The Pro-Life Alliance files are primarily composed of pro-life literature, including pamphlets, flyers, and newsletters from various national organizations. Some of the files contain information regarding the organization's activities on campus; however, these files are not particularly detailed or comprehensive. In relation to the group's work on campus, the folder containing issues of The Sophian proves to be informative as it contains a series of letters to the editor, both from the organization itself explaining its stance, and responses from the student body. The treasurer's notebook provides interesting insight into the activities of the club, as it contains many letters from students and club correspondence.
- Artifacts: t-shirt, plastic fetus model, pins, 1993-1998 (Box 3017.4)
- Budget proposal, 1995-1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 1)
- Contact list, 1993-1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 3017.2, Folder 3)
- Educational materials, 1992-1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 4)
- Events, 1994-1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 5)
- Executive board, 1991-1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 6)
- Flyers and announcements, 1996; undated (Box 3017.2, Folder 7)
- Fundraising, 1994-1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 8)
- Meeting notes, 1994-1995 (Box 3017.2, Folder 9)
- Pamphlets and literature, 1985-1995 (Box 3017.2, Folder 10)
- Petition, undated (Box 3017.2, Folder 11)
- Photographs, 1994; 1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 12)
- Press clippings, 1990; 1994 (Box 3017.2, Folder 13)
- Related organizations
  - Black Americans for Life, 1991-1992 (Box 3017.3, Folder 1)
  - Feminists for Life, 1994-1996 (Box 3017.3, Folder 2)
  - Massachusetts Blacks for Life, 1990 (Box 3017.3, Folder 3)
  - Massachusetts Citizens for Life, 1993-1994 (Box 3017.3, Folder 4)
  - N.O.W. (National Organization for Women), 1994-1996 (Box 3017.3, Folder 5)
  - National Right to Life Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 3017.3, Folder 6)
- Related publications
  - Colleges, 1994-1995 (Box 3017.3, Folder 7)
  - Human Life Alliance of Minnesota, 1996 (Box 3017.3, Folder 8)
  - Life Cycle, 1989-1994 (Box 3017.3, Folder 9)
  - Massachusetts Citizens for Life, 1994-1997 (Box 3017.3, Folder 10)
  - Newspapers and Pamphlets, 1993-1995 (Box 3017.3, Folder 11)
  - National Right to Life News, 1994-1995 (Box 3017.3, Folder 12)
  - National Right to Life News, 1996 (Box 3017.3, Folder 13)
- Sophian articles, 1996 (Box 3017.2, Folder 14)
- Speakers, 1994-1996 (Box 3017.3, Folder 14)
- Treasurer's notebook (budget reports, correspondence, pamphlets), 1993-1998 (Box 3017.2, Folder 15)